Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Board of Undergraduate Studies meeting minutes and other material
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Board of Undergraduate Studies meeting minutes and other material
1944-2010
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Board of Undergraduate Studies.
4 linear feet ((7 boxes))
Minutes and related documents of the Xavier University Board of Undergraduate Studies.
XUA- 4
History of Xavier University Board of Undergraduate Studies
The Board of Undergraduate Studies was formerly called the Academic Council. The Academic Council was created on April 18, 1944. The name of the committee changed in the Fall of 1972 to the Board of Undergraduate Studies.
The Board of Undergraduate Studies is a Xavier University Academic Committee. The role of the Board of Undergraduate Studies (formerly the Academic Council) has changed with time. The Annual Document of University Committees for 2009-2010 provides the following information on the role, responsibilities, and membership of this committee: [This committee] "1. Monitors the implementation of the University Core and is responsible for overseeing faculty votes on proposed changes to the University Core. 2. Assists in overseeing the assessment of student academic achievement in the University Core and special academic programs such as E Pluribus Unum, Scholars and HAB. 3. Works towards resolving redundancies across colleges involving: new undergraduate courses or revisions to existing undergraduate courses that are approved by the college curriculum committees. new undergraduate majors and minors or revisions to existing undergraduate majors and minors that are approved by the college curriculum committees. (Majors and minors are defined in the University Catalog.) new undergraduate programs or revisions to existing undergraduate programs that are approved by the college curriculum committees or program curriculum committees. (Programs are defined in the University Catalog.) 4. Ensures that resources exist to accommodate the requirements of new undergraduate courses, majors, minors and programs or revisions to existing undergraduate courses, majors, minors and programs when the requirements draw upon resources in other colleges. 5. Makes certain that undergraduate courses, majors, minors and programs support the Mission of the University. 6. Initiates and recommends improvements to undergraduate University Grading Policies, such as standards for Honors,standards for the Dean's List, university grading designations, and standards for graduation. 7. Initiates revisions and recommends improvements to the Undergraduate University Catalog. 8. Reviews and makes recommendations on issues concerning the scheduling of the Undergraduate Academic Calendar."..."The membership consists of six (6) tenured or tenure-track faculty members (two from each college elected by the Faculty Assembly), the deans (or their representatives) of the three colleges, three (3) students recommended by Student Government(one from each college), University Registrar (ex officio, non-voting), and the Academic Vice President/Provost (ex officio,non-voting). The chair will be elected from the faculty members by the committee." (Source: Annual Document of University Committees, 2009-2010)
Scope and Content
Meeting minutes and related materials from the Xavier University Board of Undergraduate Studies.
Not specified
Statement of Arrangement
This collection is arranged into folders chronologically. Most often related materials accompany the meeting minutes (with some exceptions).
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University Archives staff.
Accruals
There may be additional materials added to this collection at a later date.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Curriculum planning - Ohio; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Curricula
Organizations/Corporations:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Academic Council
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1944-1957 (Box 1)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1944-1947 (Folder 1)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1947-1949 (Folder 2)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1949-1951 (Folder 3)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1951-1953 (Folder 4)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1953-1955 (Folder 5)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1955-1956 (Folder 6)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1956-1957 (Folder 7)
- Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1957-1966 (Box 2)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1957-1958 (Folder 8)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1958-1959 (Folder 9)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1959-1960 (Folder 10)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1960-1961 (Folder 11)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1961-1963 (Folder 12)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1963-1965 (Folder 13)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1965-1966 (Folder 14)
- Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1966-1970 (Box 3)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1966-1967 (Folder 15)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1967-1968 (Folder 16)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1967-1968 (Folder 17)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1968-1969 (Folder 18)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1968-1969 (Folder 19)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1969-1970 (Folder 20)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1969-1970 (Folder 21)
- Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1970-1976 (Box 4)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1970-1971 (Folder 22)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1970-1971 (Folder 23)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1971-1972 (Folder 24)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1971-1972 (Folder 25)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1972-1973 (Folder 26)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1973-1974 (Folder 27)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1974-1975 (Folder 28)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1975-1976 (Folder 29)
- Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1976-1992 (Box 5)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1976-1977 (Folder 30)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1977-1978 (Folder 31)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1978-1979 (Folder 32)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1979-1980 (Folder 33)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1980-1981 (Folder 34)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1981-1982 (Folder 35)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1982-1985 (Folder 36)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1985-1988 (Folder 37)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1988-1990 (Folder 38)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1990-1992 (Folder 39)
- Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1992-1996 (Box 6)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1992-1993 (Folder 40)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1993-1994 (Folder 41)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1994-1995 (Folder 42)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1994-1995 (Folder 43)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1995-1996 (Folder 44)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1995-1996 (Folder 45)
- Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1996-2010 (Box 7)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1995-1996 (Folder 46)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1996-1997 (Folder 47)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1996-1997 (Folder 48)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1997-1998 (Folder 49)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1998-1999 (Folder 50)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 1999-2008 (Folder 51)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council), 2008-2010 (Folder 52)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies Lists of Board Decisions Additional Information, 1976-1987 (Folder 53)
  - Board of Undergraduate Studies (Academic Council) Listing of Minutes Available Electronically, 2001-2012 (Folder 54)